# **EDITO MONCADA JR**

# Software Engineer

**\( +639179473193 \)** @ editomoncada123@gmail.com

#### SUMMARY

Passionate Software Engineer with 10+ years of experience in developing web applications and backend systems. Skilled at writing clear, concise code that is easy to maintain and troubleshoot. Experienced in working with both small and large teams across multiple projects and companies. Able to work independently of remote locations or in office environments as needed by the company.

# PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

## Lead Software Engineer

01/2014 - 03/2022

# Ring System Development Inc (https://ring-group.jp/)

Philippines, Cebu

- Built, tested, and deployed scalable, highly available, and modular software products.
- Drafted comprehensive reports to document bugs and design flaws.
- Share knowledge and provide technical assistance to other team members within areas of expertise

### Software Engineer

03/2022 - Present

### Eviden (Atos Group) - (https://eviden.com/)

Philippines, Cebu

- Develop, maintain, and support new desktop and web applications.
- · Redesigned client's web-based application.
- · Presenting new features to stakeholders and customers.

#### **EDUCATION**

# Bachelor of Science in Information Technology

2009 - 2013

University of Cebu

Philippines, Cebu

#### PERSONAL PROJECT

#### ReviewPDF

A SaaS application that allows you to have conversations with any PDF documents. Simply upload your file and start asking questions right away with the power of OpenAI

- Next.is: React Framework
- · Tailwind CSS: Styling framework
- MySQL: Relational Database
- · Prisma: ORM (Object-Relational Mapping)
- tRPC: Typesafe API
- API Vercel: Cloud Hosting
- AWS RDS: Database Hosting on Amazon Web Services
- Pinecone : Vector Storage Platform
- PayPal: Payment Service



### **SKILLS**

#### Languages

Javascript · ReactJS · NextJs ·

Typescript · C# .NET CORE ·

PHP Laravel

#### SQL

MySQL · PostgreSQL · MSSQL

**CSS Frameworks** 

Tailwind · Bootstrap

**Amazon Web Services** 

EC2 · RDS · S3 · Cognito